<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Medic Supplies - News</title>
  <updated>2021-08-20T03:39:34-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Medic Supplies</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/covid-19-vaccine-what-you-should-know-before-during-and-after-the-vaccination</id>
    <published>2021-08-20T03:39:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T03:39:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/covid-19-vaccine-what-you-should-know-before-during-and-after-the-vaccination"/>
    <title>Covid-19 vaccine: What you should know before, during and after the vaccination</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Millions of people have been vaccinated against COVID-19, but many people have questions about the procedure and what to expect as a result. Check out this blog post regarding the Covid-19 vaccine: What to Expect Before, During, and After the Vaccination.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/covid-19-vaccine-what-you-should-know-before-during-and-after-the-vaccination">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Millions of individuals have now been vaccinated against COVID-19 safely throughout the world, bringing all of us a step closer to doing more activities with the people we love. The COVID-19 vaccinations were not enough for many, but of course, others had questions regarding the immunization procedure and what to anticipate in turn.</span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #c72a2a;"><b>Different COVID-19 Vaccines </b></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first vaccination offered is the finest COVID-19 vaccine. Wait, not for a certain brand. All COVID-19 vaccinations presently approved and recommended: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are safe</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Efficient</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lower the risk of severe disease</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Medic supplies do not recommend one vaccination over another. </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #c72a2a;"><b>Available Vaccination in Canada</b></span></h3>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p><b>Vaccine Brand Name</b></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><b>Who Can Get This Vaccine</b></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><b>How Many Shots You Will Need</b></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><b>When Are You Fully Vaccinated?</b></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pfizer-BioNTech</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People 12 years and older</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><b>2 shots</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given 3 weeks (21 days) apart</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 weeks after your second shot</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/different-vaccines/Moderna.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moderna</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People 18 years and older</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><b>2 shots</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given 4 weeks (28 days) apart</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 weeks after your second shot</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Johnson &amp; Johnson's Janssen</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People 18 years and older</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><b>1 shot</b></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 weeks after your shot</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br>
<h3><span style="color: #c72a2a;"><b>Tips to follow before you go for vaccination </b></span></h3>
<p><b>Do your research –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Online misinformation about vaccinations is extensive. Thus, it should always be obtained from trustworthy sources, such as UNICEF and WHO. Talk to your doctor if you have any questions about receiving a vaccination for COVID-19. A COVID-19 vaccination is not currently required to be used to prevent probable adverse events for persons with the following conditions:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there is a history of severe allergic responses to any components in the COVID-19 vaccine</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have COVID-19 symptoms or are presently ill (although you can get vaccinated once you have recovered and your doctor has approved)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Talk with your doctor –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Talk to your medication provider before an appointment if you have ever had a serious adverse response from any vaccines or if you have any issues regarding the drugs you are taking.</span></p>
<p><b>Pay attention –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Get an excellent night's rest and hydrate yourself well before your immunization to make you feel better during the day.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/covid_vaccine_480x480.png?v=1629444347" alt="covid vaccine sample" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #c72a2a;"><b>Tips to follow during the vaccination appointments</b></span></h3>
<p><b>Stay safe –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Follow safety instructions in the vaccine, such as distancing physically while waiting and carrying a mask throughout your visit.</span></p>
<p><b>Communicate – </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inform a health professional if you have any medical problems, such as pregnancy or an affected immune system, which may be considered precautions.</span></p>
<p><b>Maintain your records – </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">You should receive a vaccination card telling you when you obtained it and where you received your COVID-19 vaccine. In case you need it in the future, ensure that you stay with this card.</span></p>
<p><b>Following vaccination Stay –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The healthcare practitioner should monitor you for approximately 15 minutes after the vaccine has been delivered to ensure no instant responses. However, serious health reactions are exceedingly rare.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #c72a2a;"><b>Tips to follow after the vaccination appointments</b></span></p>
<p><b>Prepare yourself for certain side effects –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Vaccines are meant to offer you immunity without the risk of the disease. Although it is usual to increase immunity without any side effects, some mild to severe side effects are prevalent that go by themselves after a few days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the mild-to-moderate side effects you could have following vaccination include: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Arm soreness at the site of the injection </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mild Fatigue </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Headaches </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Muscle or Joint Pain </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chills </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Diarrhoea </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If symptoms last for more than a few days, or if a more serious response occurs, consult your physician.</span></p>
<p><b>Be patient –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Be patient. It takes time to build immunity. Two weeks after a second dose of the Corona Virus vaccine, 14-15 days after a second dose of the Pfizer vaccine, and two weeks after a single dose of J&amp;J/Janssen COVID-19 vaccine, you will be deemed completely vaccinated. The vaccine is considered complete two weeks later.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/covid_vaccine_1_480x480.png?v=1629444526" alt="covid sample vaccine" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><b>Stay safe for yourself and others –</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Whereas these vaccinations are quite efficient to protect people from severe COVID-19 diseases, we're still discovering if the virus may still be propagated, even without symptoms, by a vaccinated person. It is also necessary to continue to exercise security procedures, including avoiding crowding areas, distancing physically, washing the hands and using a mask.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Note that the vaccination is just a pinch. Try to overcome your fear and uneasiness while injecting. Get yourself registered for the COVID-19 vaccination on the provincial and territorial website to book your appointment. Be accountable and get immunized at your turn.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Read more about <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/covid-19-vaccines" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Covid-19 Vaccines from WHO</strong></a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although both doses of Covid-19 have been received, please remember to take preventative precautions in public areas. Note that vaccines do not guarantee complete protection. Vaccination Wear masks and follow proper hygiene methods to protect themselves and prevent the transmission of viruses. Tap the two doses and encourage others to be vaccinated according to the timetable. <a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Medic supplies</strong></a> wish each of you to stay safe and strong during these tough times!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/protect-yourself-in-2021-by-equipping-your-home-with-these-protective-equipment</id>
    <published>2021-08-13T03:25:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T03:30:43-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/protect-yourself-in-2021-by-equipping-your-home-with-these-protective-equipment"/>
    <title>Protect Yourself in 2021 by Equipping Your Home with These Protective Equipment</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Several regions of the country are beginning to open up, although there is still a risk of infection. This article outlines several items that you should keep at home so that you are not caught off guard when the next wave arrives.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/protect-yourself-in-2021-by-equipping-your-home-with-these-protective-equipment">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Several parts of the country are opening up, but there's still a risk of getting infected by this virus. Not knowing what you have to do to get through this pandemic can be stressful.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to increasing cases across the world, there are several essential changes that have been made, such as in Canada, the website </span><span style="color: #df2828;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers" target="_blank" style="color: #df2828;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>medic supplies Canada</b></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has been built to provide the necessary equipment, including masks, oxygen meters, etc. In this way, the world is gearing up against the Covid-19 virus. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article highlights certain things that you must equip at home so that you do not have to worry when the next wave hits. </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #e41111;"><b>Protective Equipment </b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most basic essentialities are things like food, water, and a warm place to sleep. It would be better to make sure that you also have basic emergency supplies on hand. </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #d41e1e;"><b>Cloth face mask</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The primary reason behind the spread of covid-19 is from person to person via respiratory droplets. Respiratory droplets travel in the air when an individual sneezes, coughs, sings, shouts, or talks. These droplets come in contact with the mouth or nose of the person who is standing nearby.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/cloth_masks_480x480.png?v=1628838504" alt="cloth face masks" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To prevent such droplets from coming in contact, <span style="color: #e21c1c;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #e21c1c;"><strong>masks</strong> </a></span>act as a barrier. According to studies, masks reduce the spray of droplets when you wear over the nose and mouth. So, for precaution, you can buy two masks for each person in your family. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There's a nationwide shortage of N95 as well as other professional masks. Healthcare workers should wear N95 masks. In case you find one, don't buy it as such masks are for health care workers. </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #d91d1d;"><b>Pulse Oximeter</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A <span style="color: #9f3131;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/digital-finger-oximeter" target="_blank" style="color: #9f3131;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>pulse oximeter</strong></a></span> is nothing but an electrical device that clips onto a patient's finger and measures heart rate and oxygen saturation in an individual's red blood cells. This device went off the stock from several online platforms such as </span>medical equipment Canada <span style="font-weight: 400;">when people came to know that low oxygen saturation is a sign of Covid-19. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/ScreenShot2020-07-22at1.49.51PM_480x480.png?v=1595440322" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coronavirus is not yet gone, so you must equip an oximeter at home. Thus, if the third wave hits, you are prepared for it. Do consider measuring heart rate twice a day. You must know that the level should be between 95 to 97. If it goes below 95, then consult a nearby doctor immediately. </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #e11f1f;"><b>First aid kit</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this challenging time, it is highly recommended to have a first aid kit. Make sure that you are stocked enough with acetaminophen. Check that the thermometer is working correctly. If not, then buy it from the nearby medical store. Finding a thermometer would be a bit challenging after the third wave hits. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/first_aid_kit_480x480.png?v=1628838800" alt="first aid kit" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #da1c1c;"><b>Medications and baby supplies</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The essential baby stuff should be refilled, such as diapers and their medications. Don't forget to buy some over-the-counter medicines which you might require. Purchase monthly-use items such as toothpaste, shampoo, soap, and toilet paper. Stock up on those items, which are extremely low right now. To get a discount on medicine or medical devices, you can search online as various online platforms offer </span><span style="color: #cc2323;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #cc2323;"><b>medical supplies for sale</b></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #cc2323;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #cc2323;">.</a></span> </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #dc1f1f;"><b>Hand sanitizer</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/2-pack-liquid-sanitizer-500ml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #ab2525;">Hand sanitizers</span></a></strong> were tough to find in the early days of the pandemic. So be prepared for the next wave by storing hand sanitizer. A sanitizer is necessary to prevent infection when you contact an infected surface; e.g., ATM can be considered a covid-19 alert place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/medic_2_480x480.png?v=1625465238" alt="hand sanitizers" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #e22020;"><b>Steam vaporizer</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You might not be able to fight the seasonal change virus. Taking warm steam is considered one of the most effective solutions for cold, cough, throat, cough, and more. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this pandemic, it is essential to take precautions against cold and cough. Hence, buying a steam vaporizer machine is a better option. In case you catch respiratory infection quite often, then consider purchasing one from the nearby medical store. </span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>Groceries</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Groceries are the most basic requirement in every home. You can purchase groceries from online platforms. However, in this pandemic, even they were not able to deliver certain items. So, to prevent such a scenario, stock up with rice, dried beans, pasta, flour, and other necessities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/groceries_480x480.png?v=1628838957" alt="groceries" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #de2222;"><b>PPE kit </b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are on corona duty or a health worker, it is essential to equip with a PPE kit. This kit is one such safety essential that would minimize the risk of infection as it covers all the parts of your body. So, consider purchasing one if you have to work in the covid-19 contentment area. </span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #e11f1f;"><b>Final verdict</b></span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a pandemic, most people live in anxiety. However, you should not be anxious when you are following all the precautions mentioned above. No one knows when the world would get rid of the covid-19 situation. But being a citizen, our role is to follow the steps mentioned by the government. So, you must equip all of the essentialities mentioned above without any delay. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/all-you-need-to-know-about-posture-correctors</id>
    <published>2021-08-03T02:49:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T03:00:56-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/all-you-need-to-know-about-posture-correctors"/>
    <title>All You Need to Know About Posture Correctors</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Bad posture, such as slouching and bending your spine for an extended amount of time, can be harmful to your physical and psychological health. Let's dig right in and see what we can do to remedy the incorrect posture.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/all-you-need-to-know-about-posture-correctors">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us admit it, we sit at our desks most of the day, slouching our backs staring at our computer screens, or spending our days hunched over our phones scrolling through memes. At the end of the day as you lie in your bed you realize you have some serious aches in your back, shoulders and neck, thanks to your bad posture!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a bad posture and slouching and bending your spine for a longer period of time can actually have adverse effects on your physical and even psychological health. Bad posture is the reason behind your imbalanced muscles that sometimes feel either too weak or too tight leading to pain, degenerative joints and discs. Let us dive in and find solutions for what can be done to correct the bad posture.</span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>Why does a good posture matter?</b></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Good posture is responsible for good musculoskeletal health. A correct posture allows for proper stacking of your bones, muscles and ligaments. This allows you to have better balance and ability to function during your daily activities like walking, standing for long periods and running or lifting as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The muscle strain caused by bad posture can be painful enough to wreak havoc on your entire body. The bad posture causes our body muscles to work overtime to realign which makes them fatigued and this results in back or neck pain.</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>Correct posture improves not just physical but also mental health</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Experts suggest that standing and sitting properly relieves pressure on your spine, neck and shoulders. This refrains your neck and back from being strained. Apart from the physical effects, experts also suggest that there are links between posture and our mental health. Research shows people with depression and anxiety have this tendency of curling inward and hunching their backs. And on the contrary, correcting the posture will automatically make people even with mental illness feel better and help them recover.</span></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/afif-kusuma-txzpx9doVWs-unsplash_480x480.jpg?v=1627972931" alt="spine posture corrector" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"> Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@javaistan?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Afif Kusuma</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/spine-posture?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a>
</div>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b></b></span></h3>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>Having a good posture will automatically:</b></span></h3>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instantly boost the mood.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secure your spine from damage.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improve your flexibility and joint movement.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decrease the risk of osteoarthritis.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improve your balance.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make breathing a lot easier giving your lungs more room to expand.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Correcting your posture requires some training and your first instinct might be to invest in a </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/smart-posture-corrector-with-sensor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>posture corrector</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #da1f1f;">.</span> You may have seen the advertisements of such posture correcting devices all over social media. And then pops up the question of doing posture correctors work? How do posture correctors help you? What devices should you choose?</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>Are posture correctors efficient enough?</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are many types of posture correctors available on the market. Having a posture corrector might be the goal but choosing the correct one is the real deal. Wrong posture correctors do not help you achieve the goal you are looking to reach, at times it does more harm than good to your body because your body becomes accustomed to these devices for holding up. This results in weakened core muscles which you would normally use for better posture as it remains relaxed. But this isn’t the case with good quality posture correctors.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/smart-posture-corrector-with-sensor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>Smart posture corrector with sensor</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> uses a different method entirely, which users have claimed to work in their favour. The built-in sensor counts the number of times good posture is broken, it buzzes for you to correct it. This device also has the sensitivity/intensity switch and voice-activated reminders. It monitors your posture in real-time and hence reminds you to correct your posture almost daily. These daily reminders strengthen your back while also training your brain to recognize it when you are slouching.</span></p>
<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/posture_corrector_480x480.png?v=1627972787" alt="posture corrector" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b></b></span></h3>
<h3><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>What to look for in a posture corrector</b></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While posture correctors do help people with maintaining good posture they are not magic wands for taking you from Neanderthal to ballerina. What posture correctors do is instead make you aware of your wrong posture and remind you to correct it. The actual benefit of these devices lies in their ability to bring awareness to your posture and that is enough to reduce the body aches and at the same time increase your confidence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You must look for a posture corrector that is comfortable to your body, gentle on you and non-rigid which does not force your body into a position that can cause pain and discomfort. Like it was mentioned above, it is not good to become completely dependent on these devices so it is recommended to use them in conjunction with a posture-strengthening exercise routine. Find the right posture corrector from any </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>wholesale medical supplies in Canada</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, here is a rundown on some of the usual types of posture correctors.</span></p>
<b>
<li>Best overall</li>
</b>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nothing could be more effective than having someone tapping you on the shoulder every time you are hunched over. Our </span>smart posture corrector with a sensor<span style="font-weight: 400;"> does that to you. The shoulder strap provides you with upper body support and aids in the prevention of bad posture and hunchback.</span></p>
<b>
<li>Best for full back support</li>
</b>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some posture correctors provide full back support; they are hooked over your shoulders like a backpack and connect over the stomach. It supports both the upper back and the lower back of your body.</span></p>
<b>
<li>A solid shoulder brace</li>
</b>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This type of brace usually supports your upper back, it is a particularly good option for a larger chest. These correctors are soft on the body and thin enough to be worn under clothes.</span></p>
<b>
<li>Braces for temporary relief</li>
</b>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the braces have their own benefits, they don’t look hideous on the surface and are not made for every activity. However there is specialty clothing with posture correction built right in, the only drawback is that it is expensive.</span></p>
<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/615b6b97-df56-4d7c-862d-07e62c71ea7f_480x480.png?v=1620855940" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
<br>
<p><span style="color: #da1f1f;"><b>In a Nutshell</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hunched backs are the problem for most of us now as we are constantly working on a laptop or looking down at our smartphones all day. Experts have explained that poor posture that is caused by sitting with your shoulders forward causes the soft muscles in your chest to get tight and having a posture corrector to make your job easier; sounds like a convenient luxury, doesn’t it?</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/how-to-pick-the-right-vitamin-supplements-for-you</id>
    <published>2021-07-20T02:53:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T02:53:51-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/how-to-pick-the-right-vitamin-supplements-for-you"/>
    <title>How to Pick the Right Vitamin Supplements for You?</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Supplements</a> have become ingrained in the life of a large number of people. Dietary supplements come in a variety of forms, including capsules, tablets, and chewable vitamins. Learn How to Choose the Best Vitamin Supplements for You.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/how-to-pick-the-right-vitamin-supplements-for-you">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supplements have become a part of the lives of so many people. Have you ever wondered why people take supplements? In an ideal world, we would get all the required vitamins and minerals from the food we eat. Considering the adulteration in food, our lifestyle and the amount of stress in our day-to-day lives, we require supplements to work at our optimum capacity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dietary supplements are consumed in the form of capsules, pills, </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #ea1a1a;"><strong><em>chewable vitamin supplements</em></strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, powders, liquid syrups, etc. comprising a blend of vitamins, minerals, antioxidants, proteins, amino acids, or probiotics in a concentrated amount to fulfil our nutritional needs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/image_2021_07_20T06_34_48_872Z_480x480.png?v=1626762982" alt="vitamins and supplements" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p>It is important to know about the functions of these nutrients in order to find the right supplements as per your requirements.</p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Vitamins</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">: Vitamins are micronutrients that are necessary for the proper functioning of our metabolism. There are two types of vitamins:</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span>
</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fat-soluble vitamins: It includes vitamin A, D, E, and K which dissolve in fat and get stored in the body.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Water-soluble vitamins: It includes vitamin B and C which are water-soluble and does not get stored in the body.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Minerals</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> Minerals are required by our body to carry out a variety of functions. They play a major role in the formation of teeth and bones, and they are involved in the functioning of the nervous system. They are an essential constituent in the production of enzymes, tissues, and body fluids.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Antioxidants</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> Antioxidants are substances that delay or prevent cell damage and up to some extent reverses the cell damage.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Proteins</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> Proteins are made up of long chains of amino acids and are building blocks for regulating our body functions. Various roles of proteins include building muscles and tissues, producing hormones, regulating the work of the immune system, storing DNA building blocks, etc. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Probiotics</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> Probiotics are bacteria that benefit the body and keep your gut healthy. They focus on developing a healthy digestive system and a healthy immune system. </span>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/image_2021_07_20T06_35_11_083Z_480x480.png?v=1626763025" alt="medic supplements" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>Do you really need a supplement?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everybody is different in how it works, what energizes it, what causes it to feel dizzy, what fuels it efficiently, and much more. A balanced diet that flourishes your health is necessary for you. Moreover, you will be able to figure out if your body is not getting its requirements fulfilled by the diet you consume. In such cases, you may have to consume some nutrients from outside to fulfil your body's requirements. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Such conditions where you may have to take vitamin supplements include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>You are above 50 years old</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> Your metabolism gets slower with age. Also, your body may not be able to absorb all the nutrients (especially B12 and vitamin D) after you reach a certain age. So, you may have to consume supplements to get enough nutrients.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>You are or might get pregnant</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> You may not get enough nutrients from food as you have to fulfil the need for yourself and your baby.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Have a limited type of diet</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> If you are a vegetarian or vegan or have some allergy to certain foods, it may be difficult to get the required nutrients. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Have a genetic disorder or certain health condition</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> You may not absorb nutrients if you have any of the conditions like cancer, inflammatory bowel disease, cystic fibrosis, liver disease, autoimmune disorder, gene mutation, etc.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #c22525;"><b>Deficiencies</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;">:</span> Deficiencies can be confirmed by blood tests. Joint pain, vision changes, extreme hair loss, tiredness, irregular heartbeat, wounds healing slowly, etc. depicts having a deficiency of nutrients in the body.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/ScreenShot2021-04-15at2.53.39PM_480x480.png?v=1618513034" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><b>Tips for consumption of vitamin supplements</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the tips to use while you get </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em><strong><span style="color: #d72020;">vitamin supplements Canada</span></strong></em></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is as follows:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Never go over the Daily Value (DV) for the supplements you take as it may cross your tolerable upper level (UL) for the nutrients which can cause an imbalance in the body and can lead to negative side effects.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are already taking some medications, consult your healthcare provider before adding any supplements to your diet as some supplements can interact with the medications you take.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Don't take vitamin supplements on an empty stomach as the vitamins like A, D, E, and K which are fat-soluble vitamins will require some food with fat for its absorption in the body.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Check the expiry date on the supplements as the quality of these supplements reduces after the expiry date. So, if you are late to open the bottle of supplements, you may not get the 100% milligrams of the nutrients mentioned on the bottle.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep your supplements in a cool and dry place as they may react to moisture if kept in a moist environment.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Choose vitamins as per your age as you may need a different set of vitamins and minerals in different forms at different stages of life. For instance, kids will be more inclined to consume chewable vitamin supplements or gummies. And after a certain age, one will need supplements to keep your eyes healthy.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy supplements from certified brands.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to vitamin supplements, we have found a solution for the consumers. Medic Supplies has been providing healthcare products across Canada for almost a decade. It also provides </span><span style="color: #de2828;"><em><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" style="color: #de2828;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>wholesale medical supplies Canada</b></a></em></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the local healthcare facilities. The most consumed products of this medical supply store</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">are listed as follows:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements/products/jamieson-chewable-vitamin-c-500-mg-tangy-orange" target="_blank" style="color: #c22525;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Jamieson Chewable Vitamin C 500 mg</strong></a>:</span> Tangy Orange: It provides a healthy immune system and has a rich source of antioxidants for the betterment of health.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #c22525;"><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements/products/jamieson-vitamin-d-1000iu-tablets-240s" target="_blank" style="color: #c22525;" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jamieson Vitamin D 1000IU Tablets 240S</a>:</strong></span> It helps with the development and maintenance of bones and teeth. It also supports phosphorus absorption in the body.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements/products/jamieson-vitamin-b-complex-timed-release" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><span style="color: #c22525;">Jamieson Vitamin B Complex Timed Release:</span></strong></a> It provides vitamin B complex and helps in converting proteins, carbohydrates, and fats to energy for living an active lifestyle. It also assists in relieving stress symptoms.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/supplements/products/jamieson-vit-b12-tr-1200mcg-tab-60w-f20-tot-80-s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #c22525;"><strong>Jamieson Vitamin B12 Tablets:</strong></span></a> Provides vitamin B12 throughout the day to energize the whole body. It also helps in the metabolism process of proteins, fats, and carbohydrates.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The daily value of consumption for vitamin C chewable tablets is 1 to 4 tablets daily.  And the daily value of consumption is 1 tablet with a meal for vitamin D, vitamin B complex, and vitamin B12 tablets. </span></p>
<h4><b>Final Words</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are considering supplements for your body, then it is advised to go with the best ones. Medic Supplies is a medical supply store with all the best supplements that one might need for maintaining a healthy body. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/demonstrate-the-science-when-and-how-to-use-hand-sanitizer-in-public-places</id>
    <published>2021-07-13T02:47:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-14T02:19:23-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/demonstrate-the-science-when-and-how-to-use-hand-sanitizer-in-public-places"/>
    <title>Demonstrate the Science - When and How to Use Hand Sanitizer in Public Places</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Sanitizers are readily available at any medical supply store. When used correctly, alcohol-based hand sanitizers can effectively inactivate a variety of pathogens. See When and How to Use Hand Sanitizer in Public Places for further information.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/demonstrate-the-science-when-and-how-to-use-hand-sanitizer-in-public-places">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to the pandemic, we have realized that germs are all over the place! They can contaminate our hands and the day-to-day objects we get into contact with, making us ill and sick. Cleaning our hands with </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/hand-sanitizers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #e72e2e;"><b>alcohol hand sanitizer</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that contain alcohol when we are prone to get attacked by these germs prevents diseases. It is one of the most important measures that we can take to avoid getting sick and transmitting germs to people around us. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To avoid getting sick and transmitting germs to others, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommends using alcohol-based hand sanitizers that contain at least 60% alcohol. We can help prevent the spread of COVID-19 and other diseases by using hand sanitizers for 20 seconds frequently, especially after using the restroom, before eating, and after coughing, sneezing, or blowing our noses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is recommended that we should wash hands with soap and water whenever possible as it decreases the number of germs and toxins on hands. However, if soap and water are not accessible, using a hand sanitizer containing at least 60% alcohol can help us in the prevention of illness and transmission of germs to others. These sanitizers can be found in any </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #e43232;"><b>medical supply store</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.</a> Alcohol-based hand sanitizers when used appropriately may inactivate several types of germs extremely efficiently. </span></p>
<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/noah-ckXArRPO8Qw-unsplash_480x480.jpg?v=1626158019" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@noahmatteo?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Noah</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/hand-sanitizers?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a>
<h2><b></b></h2>
<h2><b></b></h2>
<h2><b>When to Use Hand Sanitizers?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most of the common people and employees use their hands for the creation of different articles, to shake hands with new people, open doors, and conduct a variety of other tasks throughout a typical day. All of these activities expose our hands to potentially dangerous germs and bacteria. Given that hands transmit 80% of all illnesses, it is critical to developing an efficient hand hygiene program at work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hand hygiene compliance can save employees from absenteeism and associated expenses by 40%. While washing hands with soap and water is the greatest approach to guarantee hands are clean and germ-free, it isn't always an option. There is, however, a simple solution: hand sanitizer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Making </span><span style="color: #df2727;"><em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/hand-sanitizers/products/2-pack-liquid-sanitizer-500ml" target="_blank" style="color: #df2727;" rel="noopener noreferrer">hand sanitizer Canada</a></strong></em></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> widely available and visible is the greatest approach to remind people to use it. It is critical to have hand sanitizer near and around high-touch surfaces and common spaces, such as:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>Entrances and exit gates:</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A faulty door knob might be the source of widespread sickness in the workplace. Fresh research found that a virus placed on a doorknob was picked up by 40 to 60 percent of staff and visitors within two to four hours. So a hand sanitizer here can surely help in preventing the widespread flow of germs.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>Eateries, cafeterias, food courts, and break rooms:</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Consuming food with germ-ridden hands makes it easier to digest the germs and become sick with a variety of illnesses. The breakroom and kitchen are among the germiest areas in a workplace. Although hand sanitizer is not a substitute for anybody who prepares food, it can aid in the elimination of some bacteria.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>Places for meetings:</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Meeting rooms are frequently crammed with employees, clients, and other visitors who exchange handshakes and therefore germs. By having an easily accessible hand sanitizing station, either at the door or the table, visitors and workers may protect their hands against germs both before and after the meeting.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>Employee Desks:</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Because individuals touch them so frequently, desks, phones, computer keyboards, and computer mice are important germ transmission sites. Desks become a place where germs may survive for up to three days when eating, drinking, coughing, and sneezing. Given that employees spend the majority of their time at their workstations, putting individual hand sanitizers at each desk will keep employees' hands clean.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>High traffic areas:</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">  It is also critical to provide hand sanitizer outside of the office. Hand hygiene stations should be provided in high-traffic locations such as airport terminals, mall halls, and recreation centers to ensure that visitors stay as healthy as possible. This not only keeps high-traffic areas clean, but also serves to boost the image of the airport, mall, or recreation facility. </span>
</li>
</ul>
<br>
<h3><b><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/kelly-sikkema-iHYs3h94MNE-unsplash_1_480x480.jpg?v=1626157723" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></b></h3>
Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@kellysikkema?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Kelly Sikkema</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/hand-sanitizer?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a>
<h3><b></b></h3>
<h3><b>How to Use Hand Sanitizers?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a procedure for applying hand sanitizer, just as there is for washing our hands. We may be reducing its efficiency and perhaps leaving dangerous germs on your hands if we don't apply it appropriately. While applying hand sanitizer, four factors must be taken into consideration: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>The amount used - </b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many individuals make the mistake of using too little hand sanitizer, especially if their dispenser does not give enough in one squeeze. The World Health Organization suggests using a "coin-sized quantity" of the sanitizer. In other words, just as with hand soap, we need enough hand sanitizer to cover both sides of our hands and between our fingers.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>The technique used - </b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">After applying the sanitizer, we should thoroughly massage it. We should pay close attention to the backs of our hands, our thumbs, and the spaces between our fingers. This process should take around 20 seconds. When we're through, our hands should be completely dry. The sanitizer should not be wiped or rinsed away.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>The consistency of the sanitizer - </b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We should choose an alcohol-based hand sanitizer that has at least 60% alcohol. The Food and Drug Administration has also warned against using hand sanitizers that contain methanol, a chemical that may be harmful when rubbed into the skin. Some hand sanitizers are labeled with ethanol or ethyl alcohol yet include methanol. We should also avoid products that are not branded "FDA-approved." It is not advisable to make hand sanitizer on our own. Self-made Hand sanitizer can be useless and can even be damaging to our skin if not produced correctly.</span>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="color: #d73030;"><b>The storage of the sanitizer - </b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the expiration date approaches, the alcohol content gradually decreases, reducing its effectiveness. We should dispose of any expired hand sanitizer and replace it with a fresh bottle. We should also keep our hand sanitizer in a cold, dry place and avoid direct sunlight and prolonged heat exposure. While there is little danger of combustion, high temperatures can hasten alcohol evaporation, especially if air enters into the bottle. So a sanitizer should be properly stored. </span>
</li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Final Words</b></h4>
<span style="font-weight: 400;">With a cheap and pocket-friendly</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">hand sanitizer from any </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #d73030;"><b>wholesale medical supplies Canada</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we can help prevent the flow of diseases and create a healthier environment for the people around us.</span>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/buying-ppe-and-hand-sanitizer-in-wholesale-for-your-workplace</id>
    <published>2021-07-05T02:32:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-05T02:32:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/buying-ppe-and-hand-sanitizer-in-wholesale-for-your-workplace"/>
    <title>Buying PPE and Hand Sanitizer in Wholesale for Your Workplace</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Buying items wholesale offers a number of advantages, one of which is the cost-effectiveness of the process. This is your guide to navigating the process of purchasing PPE and hand sanitizer in bulk for your company.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/buying-ppe-and-hand-sanitizer-in-wholesale-for-your-workplace">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/medic_1_480x480.png?v=1625465594" alt="PPE and masks from medic supplies" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></strong></strong></p>
<p><strong><strong>﻿</strong></strong>The businesses have been shuttered for some time with a view to see a decline in the spread of the novel coronavirus. However, from the past 1 month or so the curve has been noticed to flatten which is why these businesses are gradually beginning to reopen for public service again but with all the safety protocols.<strong><strong><br></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although people have started to get back to work like usual, there still exists the threat of COVID-19 and the businesses have to take extra precautions when it comes to prevent and combat the COVID variants. These precautions also include stocking up the health and safety supplies, which include PPE (personal protective equipment) kits, hand sanitizers and more. However, it can be noted how difficult the supply can get when the demand is soaring high for the products, hence getting </span><span style="color: #da2727;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" style="color: #da2727;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>wholesale medical supplies in Canada</b></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> seems like a fair deal.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The wholesalers, unlike retailers, can accommodate the bulk orders of </span>medical supplies in Canada<span style="font-weight: 400;">. There's a set of advantages to buying things wholesale, one being the cost-effective method of purchasing. Here’s your guide to help you navigate the process of buying PPE and hand sanitizer wholesale for your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/medic_2_480x480.png?v=1625465238" alt="hand sanitizers from medic supplies Canada" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>The health and safety supplies you will need for reopening</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With COVID-19 hitting so bad in most parts of North America, it is recommended to all kinds of businesses irrespective of their level or location, to take precautions. Taking precautions also involves stocking up on the essential medical supplies that help reduce the transmission of the virus, these products include the following:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To begin with, have a sufficient amount of soap and water for handwashing stations at businesses and workplaces.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use alcohol-based sanitizers that consist of at least 60% alcohol.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">No-touch trash cans and tissues for the staff and customers to properly cover coughs and sneezes when need be. Although everyone is instructed to wear masks while stepping out but it is always better to be on the safer side.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy the disinfecting wipes that are disposable so that employees can wipe commonly used surfaces for their safety.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Signboards that encourage and promote proper hand hygiene to prevent the spread of germs.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Contactless hand sanitizers for places where handwashing is not a possibility.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Appropriate pair of gloves in bulk for the type of chemicals being used for the process of cleaning and disinfecting.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have no-contact payment terminals</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #d42d2d;"><em><strong>Face masks</strong></em></span></a>, disposable gloves and other types of PPE such as isolation gowns, N95 respirators, etc. based on the occupational hazards.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cleaning high-touch surfaces and objects with EPA-registered disinfectants.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy bleach solutions as alternative disinfectants for when EPA-registered disinfectants are not available.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Visual markers, signs or tapes for providing social distancing guidance.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a matter of fact, these supplies are the most necessary ones to safely reopen businesses, however, PPE and hand sanitizers are actually the toughest to come by.</span></p>
<h3><b>Why should one buy wholesale PPE and hand sanitizers?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the rising demand for safety supplies, big box stores and independent retailers themselves are struggling to keep them in stock, that is when direct wholesalers and online </span>medical supply stores<span style="font-weight: 400;"> come for your rescue.</span></p>
<h4><b>Buying wholesale and its benefits</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you want items in bulk or you are purchasing something that you are going to stock up on frequently, then shopping wholesale proves to be more beneficial. And the biggest flex is that you save good money on bulk purchases. Wholesalers offer lower prices from what traditional retailers mark up their products as customers are making purchases in larger quantities. You may not need the products immediately, purchasing in bulk quantity upfront saves you much more in the longer run. Stocking up safety products will only benefit you in the long haul. Moreover, buying wholesale gives you the peace of mind of knowing that you have enough essential safety products to last for weeks and months at a time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the time when having PPE and <a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/hand-sanitizers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #df2e2e;"><em><strong>hand sanitizers</strong></em></span></a> for your staff and customers is mandatory and it might also be the only protocol required for reopening of the businesses. The protocols of many states and provinces suggest that it is required to have masks and eye protection for the employees that interact directly with the customers which include dentists, servers in restaurants, cashiers at banks, stylists, etc. Although the entire PPE kit is not mandatory, it is still strongly encouraged by most government bodies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The growing demand for PPE and hand sanitizers are making these products much harder to find and even more expensive to purchase from traditional retailers. This leaves wholesale purchase to be the only option for small business owners, who cannot afford to put so much money on frequent purchases.</span></p>
<strong><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/medic_3_480x480.png?v=1625465134" alt="medic supplies Canada PPE" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br></strong></strong>
<h4><b>In Summary</b></h4>
<strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reopening of the businesses in the wake of COVID-19 can seem petrifying and that is what has caused the hike in demand for the PPE and hand sanitizer. Hence this seems like a good time to buy PPE and hand sanitizers in bulk from online </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #ed2525;"><b>medical supply stores</b></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to save you on the grocery store errands amidst the pandemic. Avoid going to the multiple sold-out retailers and pay premium prices just for a handful of products, instead buy them wholesale and access enough supplies for the long-term use, furthermore save money at the same time especially in times when every penny counts.</span></strong>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/what-youve-always-wanted-to-know-about-masks-but-were-afraid-to-ask</id>
    <published>2021-06-18T02:17:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-18T03:10:05-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/what-youve-always-wanted-to-know-about-masks-but-were-afraid-to-ask"/>
    <title>What You&apos;ve Always Wanted To Know About Masks But Were Afraid To Ask</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Masks have become an unavoidable part of our daily routine. Check out everything you've ever wanted to know about masks but were too afraid to ask.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/what-youve-always-wanted-to-know-about-masks-but-were-afraid-to-ask">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The COVID-19 pandemic isn't finished. Without antibodies or medications to stop COVID-19, probably the best strategy to moderate the spread of the infection is to wear a face mask, prevent the spread by hand washing, and rehearsing physical distancing as far as possible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coronavirus spreads basically from one individual to another through respiratory beads. Respiratory drops travel into the air when you hack, sniffle, talk, yell, or sing. These beads would then be able to land in the mouths or noses of individuals who are close to you or they may inhale these drops in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wearing a face mask from a </span>medical supply store<span style="font-weight: 400;"> is modest, and a viable method of restricting the transmission of the sickness. And keeping in mind that it is anything but a fix-all (physical separation is as effective as it may sound), science shows that the more an individual wears a face mask, the more we can moderate the spread of COVID-19.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the off chance that you wear a face mask, you may see sooner or later it's getting clammy, so the dampness in your breath is remaining behind and covered. The expectation is that the face mask prevents a portion of your breath from getting in contact with the air, further preventing them from tainting surfaces and individuals.</span></p>
<h1><b>How Far Can A Face Mask Keep Disease From Spreading? </b></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The face masks banter is firmly connected to another disruptive inquiry: how does the infection go through the air and spread disease? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/sick-man-wearing-mask-23SR4LP_480x480.jpg?v=1589764726" alt="disposable masks" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second an individual inhales or talks, or wheezes, a fine splash of fluid particles takes off. Some are huge — noticeable, and alluded to as droplets; others are minute and not visible to the naked eye. Infections including SARS-CoV-2 hitch rides on these particles; their size directs their conduct. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Germs can shoot through the air and land on a close-by individual's eyes, nose, or mouth whilst spreading the infection. However, gravity rapidly pulls them down. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The precision is still to be considered. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Face masks are a critical tactic to stifle transmission and save lives. If you live around Canada, check out for </span><span style="color: #de1111;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #de1111;"><b>wholesale medical supplies Canada</b></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and wrap some medical supplies for emergencies.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #e31919;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #e31919;"><b>Disposable face mask Canada</b></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ought to be utilized as a component of a thorough ‘save a life!' approach including physical distancing, staying away from swarmed, shut and close-contact settings, ensuring proper ventilation, cleaning hands, covering sniffles and hacks, and that's just the beginning.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Contingent upon the sort, disposable face masks can be utilized for one or the other insurance of sound people or to forestall ahead transmission. There's still a lot to find out about this new infection. Despite the fact individuals are currently getting inoculated, it may in any case require some serious energy before it's protected to get back to business as usual. Up to that point, wearing disposable face masks has been determined to help stop the spread of COVID-19.</span></p>
<h4><b>What Are The Different Kinds Of Face Masks? </b></h4>
<p>The act of wearing face masks to diminish the transmission of germs has a long history in certain nations. If you haven't worn a cover previously, you probably have numerous inquiries. </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, for some families, 2020 will be recognized as the first run through putting on a face mask. Here are some of the common face masks used.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/surgeon-wearing-face-mask_480x480.jpg?v=1587239785" alt="medical masks" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Face masks are a pervasive image of a pandemic that has nauseated 35 million individuals and executed more than 1 million. In emergency clinics and other </span><span style="color: #e81111;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" style="color: #e81111;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>medical supply stores</strong></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the utilization of clinical face masks unmistakably chops down transmission of the SARS-CoV-2 infection.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloth </span>disposable face mask<span style="font-weight: 400;"> - It shields others from germs inhaled out by the individual wearing it. </span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Surgical Masks - It shields the individual wearing the cover from openness to germs found in air noticeable all around. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clinical face masks - They are suggested on the off chance that you or a relative is at a higher danger of extreme disease because of COVID-19 (individuals more than 60 years of age or with basic ailments), or on the off chance that you are taking care of somebody with COVID-19. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">N95 Face masks - This gives the best degree of assurance to the individual wearing them.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">Procedural face masks - It shields the individual wearing the cover from germs noticeable all around. </li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Face masks are readily available at the </span>medical supply store<span style="font-weight: 400;">, but it is certainly not a substitute for social distancing. Face masks should in any case be worn even while maintaining social distancing, particularly when around individuals who don't live in your family. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Face masks cover the nose and mouth and fit cozily against the sides of the face without holes. They ought to be worn at all times when stepping out of your house, for example, the time you are going on a plane, car, train, or another type of public transportation. </span></p>
<h4><b>When Shouldn't You Wear A Face Mask? </b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Face masks ought not to be worn by any individual who can't eliminate the cover without assistance, including babies and little youngsters, or anybody experiencing issues while breathing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">UNICEF and WHO suggest that youngsters matured 5 years and under ought not to be needed to wear face masks. The suggestion is entirely based on the child’s wellbeing and perceives that a kid’s growth may be hindered due to masks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/kelly-sikkema-RYABMCLP7aM-unsplash_480x480.jpg?v=1623911567" alt="disposable face masks" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@kellysikkema?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Kelly Sikkema</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/mask?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p>
<p>A few nations have various suggestions on cover use by kids, so it's critical to check with your neighborhood experts on any age-explicit necessities. If they require kids matured 5 years and under to wear face masks, you or another guardian ought to be able to administer and protect the face mask. </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you or a relative has a medical issue or incapacity that makes it hard to wear the </span><span style="color: #f21717;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #f21717;"><b>disposable face mask</b></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, check with your primary care physician for guidance on what is best for you. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The information of face mask is still chaotic, different, and hurriedly collected without much discretion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When working out, pick a place where wearing a face mask isn't required, for example, at home or in a space (like outside) where you can stay away from others. Kids and grown-ups ought not to wear face masks when playing sports or doing proactive tasks, so it doesn't bargain their breathing issues. Sweat can likewise cause the cover to get wet, making it hard to inhale and simpler for germs to develop, doing more worse than good.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Read more - </span></p>
<p class="article--title"><span style="color: #e61d1d;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/everything-you-need-to-know-about-masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #e61d1d;"><strong><em>Everything You Need To Know About Masks</em></strong></a></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/add-these-essential-medical-supplies-to-your-first-aid-kit-to-make-it-more-comprehensive</id>
    <published>2021-06-10T03:34:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T03:26:10-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/add-these-essential-medical-supplies-to-your-first-aid-kit-to-make-it-more-comprehensive"/>
    <title>Add These Essential Medical Supplies To Your First-Aid Kit To Make It More Comprehensive</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Although ready-made first-aid kits are available at over-the-counter stores, it is always possible to make and have your own easy and affordable first-aid kit, so select from the many medical supplies that are readily accessible.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/add-these-essential-medical-supplies-to-your-first-aid-kit-to-make-it-more-comprehensive">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A first-aid kit is a prerequisite to healthy living. Every year unintentional injuries are leading to millions and millions of medical visits. The only way to safeguard yourself from medical emergencies is to be prepared. Common and mild injuries can be treated with a few medical essentials at home. Everyone needs a first-aid kit at some time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/Add_These_Essential_Medical_Supplies_To_Your_First-Aid_Kit_To_Make_It_More_Comprehensive_240x240.png?v=1623311442" alt="Upgrade your first aid kit by adding some of these medical supplies" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, take adequate time to prepare it and have it available for home and travel. Preparing a first-aid kit is no rocket science, but a careful purchase decision from a </span>medical supply store<span style="font-weight: 400;">. You need to assemble the important equipment and personalize it as per your family’s requirements. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While designing a first-aid kit, don’t worry about making it a hospital bag. It can be as basic as possible and comprehensive at the same time. What you personalize in the first-aid kit entirely depends on any medical training or the help from a professional in that manner. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although there are ready-made first-aid kits available at over-the-counter stores it is always feasible to create and have your own simple and inexpensive first-aid kit, so choose from the widely available </span><strong><em><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">medical supplies Canada</a></em></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and assemble the kit. Customize it as per the needs and emergencies of you and your family. Stock all the necessary equipment when putting together your first aid kit and therefore make sure the below items are unnecessarily present.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before diving into the essential items, always note that the essentials of a first-aid kit should last at least 6 to 8 months or for that matter up to a year. Always have your medical information inside the first-aid kit so you can glance at it whilst you take up your medicine. First-aid kits are the beginning of care and should not be considered primary care. Once a first aid is done make sure to rush to a doctor or the nearby hospital and give the person the necessary medical attention. </span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Personal Items</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start with personal items as the first ingredients of your first aid kit. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A list of emergency contact numbers, for example, those of local hospitals, the police station, doctors, dentists, gynecologists, and important family contacts. If your family member is a regular user of insulin, a few doses in the first-aid kit will help counter sudden emergencies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make sure you keep a check on the quantity of medicine available for special diseases such as arthritis, diabetes, liver, and kidney ailments. Do not unbox the medicines from the original container and store them together with other medicines. Make sure the medicines are stored in the actual containers they are delivered. You can make an inexpensive kit and look for </span>wholesale medical supplies Canada<span style="font-weight: 400;"> for an easy purchase.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep a regular check on the expiration date. Insulin primarily should be kept in a cool place. You can also put a sticky note to remind yourself of the time you should take your insulin so that it is not forgotten. </span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Cotton Balls And Cutips</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make a point to place them in a perfect box inside your first aid box. You will not be helping anybody by utilizing a dirty cotton ball or a pad. So keep it clean, and use it only when needed. There is no question of the cotton pad expiring, as such storing for long is quite a feasible option.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3><span style="color: #f20b0b;"><em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/non-contact-infrared-thermometer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #f20b0b;">Non-Contact Infrared Thermometer</a></strong></em></span></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since you can't generally utilize the rear of your hand to tell when you're having a fever. If you have babies at home, this is an unquestionable requirement. The non-contact thermometer lets you determine body temperature from a distance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, that’s true.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/4_480x480.jpg?v=1608274523" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The device is capable of creating a temperature alert warning and has an automatic power-off feature, a thoughtful device to keep you worry-free during emergencies.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Band-aid</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A pre-eminent medical item that is of use to anybody and everybody. From chopping vegetables in the kitchen to conducting gardening operations on the balcony, minor cuts and bruises are common encounters. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Band-aid helps heal better and also keeps the area prevented from further exposure. You can apply a drying powder on the wounded area before applying the band-aid and further renew the band-aid every time the adhesive loosens. </span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Face Masks</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given the sudden emergency alarming the planet with thousands of cases of Covid 19, <span style="color: #ff0000;"><em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #ff0000;">face masks</a></strong></em></span> have become pre-emptive equipment of the first aid kit.</span></p>
<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/Healthcanadamaskx200_480x480.png?v=1591025254" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It not only prevents the spread of infection but helps maintain social distancing when at times it’s not possible.  </span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Safety Pins</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two reasons: self these pins are flexible - they prove to be useful for closet crises, as well; and when you break the fastener on your crêpe gauze, you'll need a security pin to keep the set up in place.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Creams and Ointments</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category also includes antiseptic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wounds, cuts, and bruises need to be cleaned immediately to prevent skin irritations and infections. Hydrogen peroxide, antibacterial soap, or pain reliever can be of great help. Creams and ointment may include aloe vera gel and anti-itching cream or a coolant that can be applied over burnt areas. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aloe vera gel is considered soothing for treating burns as well as moisturizes the skin. Instead of using antibacterial soap, you can also use a liquid topical solution or antiseptic wipes if you have sensitive skin. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A liquid topical solution may cause sensitivity initially, so make sure you apply for pain relief once the wounded area is cleaned.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Sanitizers</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just when you quickly need to make your hands germ-free, without wasting time, and water - <span style="color: #f20606;"><em><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/hand-sanitizer-8oz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #f20606;"><strong>sanitizers</strong> </a></em></span>are the guardian angels. </span></p>
<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/sanitizerspray_480x480.jpg?v=1601521970" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A first aid kit should be administered with germ-free hands, and any dressing done should follow the same. Moreover, sanitizers do not cause skin irritation like soap and water and are an easy option of precaution.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Pain Relievers</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is a need for reducing the pain from a physical issue or disease. Keep a container of pain relievers available, for example, ibuprofen, anti-inflammatory medicine, acetaminophen, and a non-ibuprofen pain reliever for youngsters, or all of the above.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ibuprofen is useful for migraines, cuts, fevers, and joint pain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acetaminophen likewise assists with migraines, yet dissimilar to ibuprofen. It will not assist with muscle torment or injuries. Ibuprofen can likewise dispose of migraines, help relieve joint and muscle pain, lower fevers, and decrease irritation, making it an extraordinary alternative if you have a seasonal disease. </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b><span style="color: #ef0a0a;">Wholesale medical supplies Canada</span> </b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">will not be harsh on your pocket and convenient to pack all multi use items.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ibuprofen isn't suggested if a kid has had an infection, as it can prompt Reye's syndrome.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Scissors</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The requirement of a scissor is clear as crystal. Simply be mindful so as not to cut yourself. What's more, perhaps get a baby-proof one if you have small kids in the house – dressings are not that difficult to cut.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The idea of first aid should be simple with contents that offer visibility. Stock it with multi-use things. Nearly anything that gives great perceivability of substance, and can be utilized for a family emergency treatment. A progressive first aid kit should have a syringe and a spill-proof container. You can also store nylon sacks or make-up cases as spill-proof containers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You don't have to spend a great deal of cash, instead use handy items, and have easy substitutes.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Oximeters</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/ScreenShot2020-07-22at1.49.51PM_480x480.png?v=1595440322" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regular monitoring of the oxygen saturation can prevent a lot of mishaps. Low oxygen levels can be countered in time, and the need for oxygen can be met. <span style="color: #fc0c0c;"><em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/digital-finger-oximeter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #fc0c0c;">Pulse oximeters</a> </strong></em></span>are available for purchase online in Canada at reasonable rates for usage on a regular basis to monitor the health of those suffering from diseases that alter blood oxygen levels.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/tips-for-maintaining-and-caring-for-your-nebulizer</id>
    <published>2021-06-03T03:24:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-03T03:34:29-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/tips-for-maintaining-and-caring-for-your-nebulizer"/>
    <title>Tips For Maintaining And Caring For Your Nebulizer</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A nebulizer converts liquid medication into a mist that the patient may breathe straight into the lungs. Check out these useful tips for keeping and caring for your nebulizer.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/tips-for-maintaining-and-caring-for-your-nebulizer">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A nebulizer turns medication from a liquid to a mist for the patient to inhale directly into the lungs. A </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/portable-handheld-nebulizer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>portable nebulizer</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> runs on batteries or can be plugged into a car outlet. You can easily carry them in a bag or a briefcase.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Owning a nebulizer requires you to have a doctor’s prescription, or you can directly get it from your pediatrician’s office. People often get breathing treatment at their doctor’s office as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If prescribed by doctors, you can easily find these portable nebulizers from </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>online medical supply stores in Canada</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.</a> Portable nebulizers usually cost a little higher than regular ones.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/49451ab9-0908-45e9-9985-b1d20d221b34_480x480.png?v=1614000384" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>Types of Nebulizers</b></h2>
<h3><b>Jet</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jet nebulizers make use of compressed gas for making an aerosol, i.e. tiny particles of medication in the air.</span></p>
<h3><b>Ultrasonic</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultrasonic nebulizers make an aerosol using high-frequency vibrations; the particles are larger compared to the jet nebulizer.</span></p>
<h3><b>Mesh</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mesh nebulizers form the aerosol by passing the liquid through a very fine mesh. These nebulizers have the smallest particles of all, and it also is the most expensive of them all.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now let us have a look at how to clean and care for your portable nebulizers while you use them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nebulizers come in handy for people with breathing challenges. However, like all other medical supplies, even </span><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/portable-handheld-nebulizer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>portable nebulizers</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> need good cleaning and maintenance to work at their optimum. Here are some compelling ways to care for your nebulizer.</span></p>
<h2><b>Why is it required to keep it clean?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before you get into a routine of cleaning your nebulizers, you must first understand why it is crucial. You need to keep it clean for it to work correctly and at its best. Without periodic cleaning and proper maintenance, the jet holes or mesh holes in the nebulizer are likely to get clogged, leading to a reduction in the amount of medicine being released. Improper cleaning routine also gives rise to bacterial growth in the nebulizers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/240d90e0-16a2-4054-b5a9-4614b3d66385_480x480.png?v=1614000384" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><b>Daily cleaning steps</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make sure your nebulizers maintain peak performance with these basic cleaning steps after each use, followed by some intense cleaning once a week or so.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have a jet nebulizer, rinse the nebulizer cup entirely with warm water, throw off excess water and let it air-dry, do this after each treatment. Wash the cup and mask or mouthpiece in warm water with a mild detergent almost on a daily basis. Rinse entirely and leave it to air-dry. There is no need to clean the compressor tubing.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have a mesh nebulizer, you will have to pour out leftover medicine and segregate the mouthpiece from the handset. Make routine cleaning a practice, wash in a bowl of warm water and liquid dish soap, rinse and let it air-dry. Avoid rinsing the handset.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>Weekly cleaning steps</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apart from the daily cleaning, you will also have to disinfect your nebulizer every week.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a mesh nebulizer, first, start with boiling the mouthpiece for 10 minutes or so. While doing so, make sure that the medication chamber is open, and the mouthpiece is not touching the bottom of the pan. Later, leave it to air-dry. Also, wipe the handset with a clean damp cloth during weekly cleaning.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a jet nebulizer, boil the parts of the nebulizer in soapy water except for the tubing or mask for about 10 minutes. Later, rinse under running water for 2 minutes and leave it to air-dry.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some experts even recommend soaking the nebulizer cup and mask or mouthpiece in a solution of vinegar and water thrice a week. However, the best way to conclude best practice for yourself is to talk to your doctor, follow their advice and read the recommendations that come with the nebulizers; this will ensure you are following all the guidelines closely.</span></p>
<h3><b>Storing tips</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is also important to understand how to maintain nebulizers when you are not using them.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">After complete rinsing and drying, wipe the compressor with a clean and damp cloth and cover it with a clean cloth.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid keeping the compressor on the floor, whether it be for treatment or storage.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Store your medication in dry places and cool areas with no harsh heat exposure. Some medicines are required to be kept in the refrigerator, while others work fine by just being kept out of the light. However, you must check them often to see if they changed colour or formed crystals; in that case, throw them away and replace them.</span></li>
</ul>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/a-brief-guide-to-understanding-pulse-oximeter-better</id>
    <published>2021-05-24T02:45:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T02:38:39-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/a-brief-guide-to-understanding-pulse-oximeter-better"/>
    <title>A Brief Guide To Understanding Pulse Oximeter Better</title>
    <author>
      <name>SEO Web</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="row clearfix content-line">
<div class="col-xs-9 column content-util">
<article><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/digital-finger-oximeter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pulse oximeters</a> let you check your blood oxygen saturation in the privacy of your own home. Here's a quick guide to help you properly understand pulse oximetry.</article>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row clearfix content-line"></div><p><a class="read-more" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/a-brief-guide-to-understanding-pulse-oximeter-better">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p id="c685" class="hh hi fq hj b hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Pulse oximeters are generally, like other medical supplies, found in doctor’s offices and hospitals. But now, with the rise in COVID-19, people have bought this equipment home for use. Pulse oximeters help you keep track of your blood oxygen saturation from the comfort of your home. It is a small device that quickly and painlessly measures the oxygen saturation level.</p>
<h2 id="f599" class="ib ic fq ba id ie if hl ig ih ii ho ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu iv iw dy"><strong class="bk">How does a pulse oximeter work?</strong></h2>
<p id="722a" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">One thing about pulse oximeters that are<span id="rmm"><span> </span></span>actually called over-the-counter (OTC) oximeters is that they are made for home use; they are easier to use for people who are not healthcare professionals. These oximeters are smaller in size meant for spot-checks; they are cheaper and easier to use. Some of these OTC oximeters even have special features that suit your day-to-day needs.</p>
<p class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/ScreenShot2020-07-22at1.49.51PM_480x480.png?v=1595440322" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""> </p>
<p id="23c6" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ju hl hm hn jv ho hp hq jw hr hs ht jx hu hv hw jy hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">The device typically has a clip-like design; you have to attach them to your finger, toe or earlobe. Pulse oximeters use beams to measure your blood oxygen levels. Unlike the conventional method where you have to get your body part pricked, these beams pass through your blood in that area.</p>
<p id="bda8" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ju hl hm hn jv ho hp hq jw hr hs ht jx hu hv hw jy hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Technically, a pulse oximeter determines the percentage of oxygen in the blood as it shines light through the attached body part to analyze the amount of light that passes through the blood. However, the amount of light absorbed by the blood differs depending on how oxygenated the blood is.</p>
<h3 id="406f" class="ib ic fq ba id ie if hl ig ih ii ho ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu iv iw dy"><strong class="bk">What are pulse oximeters used for?</strong></h3>
<p id="2ced" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Your blood oxygen level becomes a determining factor of how well the heart pumps oxygen throughout the body. This makes it a critical device in hospital settings; it can quickly alert doctors of low oxygen levels in patients. It helps doctors assess the need for oxygen in patients, making them respond well to supplemental oxygen. However, in the face of covid-19, these devices are proving to be life-saving. Buy<span> </span><span style="color: #404040;"><em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/digital-finger-oximeter" class="bv jz" rel="nofollow" style="color: #404040;">pulse oximeters in Canada</a></strong></em></span><span> </span>from trusted sellers to be used at home for monitoring and providing peace of mind. It can be used by people with conditions that may cause them to experience periods of low oxygen levels.</p>
<p class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">These conditions include anaemia, asthma, pneumonia, lung cancer and more such diseases. Even doctors prescribe a pulse oximeter to people with these conditions to monitor oxygen levels while exercising, travelling at high altitudes or taking medication.</p>
<h3 id="d6a3" class="ib ic fq ba id ie if hl ig ih ii ho ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu iv iw dy"><strong class="bk">Pulse oximeter and covid-19</strong></h3>
<p id="b361" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Pulse oximeters are playing a massive role in the covid era. Patients suffering from covid can experience a sudden drop in blood oxygen levels without experiencing shortness of breath. The use of a pulse oximeter could alert you when this drop occurs in the blood oxygen levels before it gets severe. However, it is not a replacement for a consultation with a health professional. Plus, the low saturation of oxygen in the blood is not the only symptom of COVID-19.</p>
<p id="0d2a" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ju hl hm hn jv ho hp hq jw hr hs ht jx hu hv hw jy hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Note — If you use a pulse oximeter, it is vital to be conscious of other coronavirus symptoms alongside. Consult your doctor in case you experience these symptoms despite the device showing you healthy blood oxygen levels.</p>
<p class="hh hi fq hj b hk ju hl hm hn jv ho hp hq jw hr hs ht jx hu hv hw jy hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/ScreenShot2020-07-22at1.24.11PM_640x640.png?v=1614002026" width="468" height="494" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<h3 id="4a42" class="ib ic fq ba id ie if hl ig ih ii ho ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu iv iw dy"><strong class="bk">Why is it necessary to keep your blood oxygen level in check?</strong></h3>
<p id="5fc6" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">When your blood oxygen levels are low, it becomes hard for your body to pump oxygen to your cells and tissues. The lowered blood oxygen level declines your bodily functions and puts an extra strain on your heart and brain. It is crucial for people with chronic conditions to check their blood oxygen levels on a regular basis. With the proper knowledge, you can get supplemental oxygen or required medical care to prevent cells and tissue damage.</p>
<h4 id="c7c4" class="kc ic fq ba id kd ke kf ig kg kh ki ij kj kk kl in km kn ko ir kp kq kr iv ks dy"><strong class="bk">Consider these factors when you want to find the right pulse oximeter.</strong></h4>
<ul class="">
<li id="d318" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia kt ku kv dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><em class="kw">Physical characteristics</em></li>
<li id="38cc" class="hh hi fq hj b hk kx hl hm hn ky ho hp hq kz hr hs ht la hu hv hw lb hx hy ia kt ku kv dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><em class="kw">Monitoring duration</em></li>
<li id="c66a" class="hh hi fq hj b hk kx hl hm hn ky ho hp hq kz hr hs ht la hu hv hw lb hx hy ia kt ku kv dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><em class="kw">Movement of the patient</em></li>
<li id="8a88" class="hh hi fq hj b hk kx hl hm hn ky ho hp hq kz hr hs ht la hu hv hw lb hx hy ia kt ku kv dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><em class="kw">Mitigating cross-contamination</em></li>
<li id="d833" class="hh hi fq hj b hk kx hl hm hn ky ho hp hq kz hr hs ht la hu hv hw lb hx hy ia kt ku kv dy" data-selectable-paragraph=""><em class="kw">Use of certified sensors</em></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5623" class="kc ic fq ba id kd ke kf ig kg kh ki ij kj kk kl in km kn ko ir kp kq kr iv ks dy"><strong class="bk">Where can you get a pulse oximeter?</strong></h3>
<p id="8373" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ix hl hm hn iy ho hp hq iz hr hs ht ja hu hv hw jb hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">In some cases, even doctors prescribe you or may provide you with the pulse oximeter if they believe monitoring your oxygen levels at home is mandatory. Apart from that, you can easily find them on the market or even online. Medic supplies are known for selling<span> </span><strong><em><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" class="bv jz" rel="nofollow">wholesale medical supplies Canada-wide.</a></em></strong></p>
<p id="3953" class="hh hi fq hj b hk ju hl hm hn jv ho hp hq jw hr hs ht jx hu hv hw jy hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Pulse oximetry is an easy and non-invasive method of checking your oxygen saturation levels, and it allows you to take action before other symptoms occur. Make sure you talk to your doctor first before you start using a pulse oximeter so as to receive the maximum benefits.</p>
<p class="hh hi fq hj b hk ju hl hm hn jv ho hp hq jw hr hs ht jx hu hv hw jy hx hy ia dh dy" data-selectable-paragraph="">Read more about oximeters - <a href="https://www.who.int/patientsafety/safesurgery/pulse_oximetry/who_ps_pulse_oxymetry_tutorial2_advanced_en.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong><span style="color: #ea1919; text-decoration: underline;">Using Pulse Oximeters - Tutorial By WHO</span></strong></em></span></a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/everything-you-need-to-know-about-masks</id>
    <published>2020-05-18T10:47:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T03:20:03-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/everything-you-need-to-know-about-masks"/>
    <title>Everything You Need To Know About Masks</title>
    <author>
      <name>Mifo Canada</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The novel coronavirus has really changed the way we live day to day and until a vaccine is available, we can expect that these changes may last a while. So how do we protect ourselves? By using protective equipment that health professionals have been successfully using for years. The only question is, how do we know what type of mask we need? What about telling the difference between quality compared to fakes. We're going to go over everything you need to know to keep yourself and loved ones safe!</p>
<h2>
<strong>What Does PPE Mean?</strong> </h2>
<p> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/surgeon-in-operating-room-at-hospital-PH2XD8K_large.jpg?v=1586798918" alt=""></p>
<p>Let's start with the basics. PPE is the common acronym for <strong>Personal Protective Equipment</strong>. It is used to refer to garments or equipment specially designed to protect the wearer (previously mostly used by workers) from occupational hazards which include physical, chemical, mechanical, electrical, biological, and radiological hazards. The workplace is open to all forms of hazards and risks and therefore, it is vital that adequate protective measures are put in place. </p>
<p>Wearing protective gear that is well-fitting and properly maintained is a great way to prevent accidents and improve safety in the workplace. All employees should be adequately sensitized on the importance of adhering to PPE safety rules in the workplace. Some examples of PPE are hard hat (safety helmet), gloves, earplugs, face masks, goggles, work boots, etc. One major way to stop or at least reduce the spread of airborne viruses such as the Coronavirus is by wearing face masks by both healthy and infected people. </p>
<p>Most PPE protects the wearer and is completely ineffective if not worn properly or is defective in any way. It also restricts the wearer to a certain degree. If the PPE is defective, fake in any way, or isn’t worn properly, the wearer is at a greater risk of the hazard because it may give the wearer a false sense of confidence</p>
<p>During these times, PPE is rapidly becoming a must-have to protect yourself when having to be out and around others. Let's dive into the most common PPE we are seeing around, masks.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>
<strong>Masks</strong> </h2>
<p> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/KN95-11_large.jpg?v=1586814032" alt=""></p>
<p>Disposable masks (also called medical, dental, surgical, laser, or procedure masks) are face masks used by medical personnel to prevent the spread of diseases. Face masks are able to protect the wearer to a certain degree if worn properly. Characteristics of face masks are that they are tight-fitting, and they cover the nose and mouth. They also have loops for the ears or come with ties or bands that go to the back of the head. They are many different types of face masks, made of different materials for different purposes. </p>
<p>Face masks help reduce the spread of germs and diseases. When a person who is sick talks, coughs, or sneezes, they are likely to release droplets that carry the disease-causing agent into the atmosphere which can infect others. By wearing a face mask, an infected person reduces the number of people they are likely to infect. Also, face masks protect the wearer from sprays of body fluids that are likely to carry disease-causing agents. </p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Types of Face Masks</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/product-image-1337403854_medium.jpg?v=1588527774" style="float: none;"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Surgical Masks (Medical Masks)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>They are loose-fitting <a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/50-disposable-masks-set" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em><strong>disposable masks</strong></em></a> that help protect the wearer from sprays or splashes of bodily fluid that may contain disease-causing germs. Surgical masks help filter the air and protect others too.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/products/product-image-1353546889_medium.jpg?v=1586978013" style="float: none;"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>N95 Masks/KN95</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>The <a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks/products/kn95-masks-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em><strong>N95 /KN95 mask</strong></em></a> is a type of respirator that offers more protection than the medical mask because it is able to filter out both big and small particles while the medical mask is only able to filter out big particles. The name includes 95 because it is able to block out 95% of small particles. They are also meant to be disposable. </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/6470f22f-2036-445c-820e-f8923a751ab8_1.4add87911cde2f2adf74f3bd83185d37_medium.jpeg?v=1589763206" style="float: none;"></div>
<br>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cloth Masks</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>When surgical and N95 masks are unavailable, the next best thing is the cloth mask. <em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/products/reusable-face-mask" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cloth masks</a></strong></em> protect others from the wearer, unlike the surgical and N95 masks that protect the wearer from others. Cloth masks are cheap and easy to make. They can be made from a variety of breathable materials such as tightly woven cotton. They can also be fashioned out of items such as t-shirts and bandanas but must be layered multiple times for best results. Also, because cloth masks offer little protection compared to medical masks and N95’s, there have to be additional safety procedures to follow.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Mask Strength</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/attractive-student-of-chemistry-working-in-lab-8YMT34D_cdf77f6a-95d7-4995-bfd5-cdc06d007303_large.jpg?v=1589763641" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Typically, there are three levels for determining the strength (its ability to resist the penetration of synthetic blood) of facial masks. </p>
<ul>
<li>Level 1 has low barrier protection and is used for medical exams and short procedures that do not involve sprays or fluids.</li>
<li>Level 2 has moderate barrier protection and can be used where there is moderate spray or fluids.</li>
<li>Level 3 has maximum barrier protection and is used for situations with heavy spray or fluid. The minimum resistant pressure of the level 3 mask is twice that of a level 1 mask. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>How to Wear Medical Face Mask</strong></h2>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/sick-man-wearing-mask-23SR4LP_large.jpg?v=1589764726" alt=""> </p>
<p><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/masks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em><strong>Medical face masks</strong></em></a> are disposable, hence they should be used only once and thrown away. Also, when the face mask becomes moist, they should be thrown away. Always follow the instructions on the face mask packaging on how to wear them. Below are some guidelines to follow when wearing face masks:</p>
<ol>
<li>Wash your hands thoroughly prior to handling the face mask or use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer to clean your hands.</li>
<li>Take the mask from its packaging and inspect it for factory defects on any part. </li>
<li>Identify the topside of the mask. The top is distinguishable by the flexible supple area that fits the structure of the nose.</li>
<li>Identify the front and back of the mask. <br><strong>N.B</strong>: There are two sides to the medical masks. One side is coloured, while the other side is white. The coloured part of the mask is the front, wear this facing outward while the white part will be in contact with your face. </li>
<li>To wear face masks that have ties, bring the mask to your face at nose level and secure it with a bow at the back of your head. To wear face masks that have ear loops, bring your mask close to your face, using the ear loops, and then place each loop around ears.</li>
<li>Mold the rigid sides of the mask around the shape of your nose.</li>
<li>Draw the lower part of your mask over your mouth and chin to complete the protection.</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong></strong></h2>
<h2><strong>How To Remove Medical Masks</strong></h2>
<p> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/masks-infographic---final_large.png?v=1589765476" alt=""></p>
<p>Remember that once used, medical face masks are contaminated and should be disposed of immediately. Care should be taken when disposing of them to avoid contaminating yourself again. Some guidelines on removing medical masks are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Wash your hands with soap and running water or use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer to clean your hands.</li>
<li>Do not touch the front of the mask as that is the part that has been contaminated. Hold the mask only by the ear loops or ties.</li>
<li>When removing face masks that have ear loops, hold the mask by the ear loops and carefully remove them. Be careful not to let the mask or your hand touch your face. For masks with ties, untie the bow(s) and pull the mask away from your face.</li>
<li>Throw the face mask in the bin and wash your hands with plenty of soap lather and water or use a hand sterilizer. Do not touch your face until you have washed your hands.  </li>
</ol>
<p> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/close-up-view-of-scientist-in-mask-PBF82KU_large.jpg?v=1589766325" alt=""></p>
<p>For people who wear glasses, it is not uncommon that while wearing a facial mask, their glasses get fogged up. This is because while breathing, the air would sometimes travel upwards causing the glass to form fog. There are also other factors that may cause your glass to get fogged up such as the weather, the fit of the mask on your face, and the quality of the mask. However, here are some tips to try when your glasses are fogging up while wearing facial masks:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>Adjust the fit of the mask. If your mask is too loose, it may leave room for your breath to escape upwards and cause your glasses to fog. Try tightening your mask strap at the bridge of your nose if it is the type with ties or finds a mask with a better fit. </li>
<li>Adjust the position of the mask and glasses on your face. You may want to bring the mask a little lower down your nose but ensure it still covers a majority of your nose and your entire mouth. Then raise your glasses a little higher but avoid touching your face.</li>
<li>Wash your glasses with soap and water. Allow them to air-dry to prevent fogging. This creates a layer of film that prevents fogging. </li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Testing Your Medical Mask</strong></h2>
<p> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/030420_realvsfakemask_yt2_large.png?v=1589765726" alt=""></p>
<p>Due to a shortage of medical masks, there are now lots of fakes circulating in the markets. These fakes are unable to protect you because they are made using substandard products for the sole purpose of making a profit. Wearing a fake mask is as good as not wearing any at all. There are two major ways to test your face mask is real:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Visual Test:</strong> Medical face masks are supposed to be 3-ply consisting of the inner layer, which is white, the middle layer which is a filter (not paper), and the outer layer which is usually green. To do the visual test, you need to cut open one side of the mask to confirm all layers are intact and correct.</li>
<li>
<strong>Water Test:</strong> The outer layer of the medical mask is meant to be waterproof to protect you against other people and bodily fluids carried through coughing and sneezing. To do the water test, fold the mask to form a funnel with the outer part and then pour some water in. The mask should be able to hold water properly.</li>
<li>
<strong>Breath Test:</strong> Medical masks hold the wearer's particles from spreading. Perform the breath test by grabbing a lighter and hold a flame far enough away from your face. Blow into the mask attempting to put the flame out. It should be harder to do so if the air is limited through a quality mask.</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Donating Medical Supplies</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<p>The WHO is working with certain organizations to help in the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic. They have a list of organizations that are happy to receive donations from individuals and corporates. The list can be found here: <span><a href="https://www.who.int/medical_devices/management_use/donation_org_roles.pdf">https://www.who.int/medical_devices/management_use/donation_org_roles.pdf</a></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/helping-fight-covid-19</id>
    <published>2020-03-15T21:17:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-22T02:37:05-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medicsupplies.ca/blogs/news/helping-fight-covid-19"/>
    <title>Helping Fight COVID-19</title>
    <author>
      <name>Mifo Canada</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="s4"><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0286/9500/3196/files/covid-19-23-W9YXPCL.jpg?v=1588695230" alt=""></span></p>
<p class="s4">At Medic Supplies we know we have a social responsibility to help fight COVID-19. To help battle COVID-19 we have taken it upon ourselves to help our most at-risk populations by; <br><br><strong><span class="s2">1. Designating our inventory to those most at risk:</span></strong> We have made sure <a name="_GoBack"></a>that those that need <em><strong><span style="color: #e71d1d;"><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" style="color: #e71d1d;" rel="noopener noreferrer">protective personal equipment</a></span></strong></em>(PPE) most such as frontline healthcare workers and those in long term care settings have priority to our inventory.<br><br><strong><span class="s2">2. Donations:</span></strong> As there is a tremendous shortage in supply of PPE in our hospitals and long term care centers we are doing our part to give back by donating PPE. <br><br><strong>3. Educating our clients:</strong> We have weekly newsletters in which our medical directors help summarize the latest updates in the pandemic and help provide tips to keep you and your family safe.<br><br>From the medic supplies family to yours, we have outlined some useful information to help answer some of the questions you may have about the coronavirus:<br><br><strong><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">What is COVID-19 and what are the symptoms?</span></span></strong></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s7"><span class="bumpedFont15">Coronaviruses are very common in animals worldwide, but only a handful of them are known to affect humans.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s9"><span class="bumpedFont15">Usually, symptoms are like a common </span></span><span class="s7"><span class="bumpedFont15">cold, though in some cases, the viruses can cause lower-respiratory tract illnesses such as pneumonia and bronchitis. </span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s7"><span class="bumpedFont15">There is no current medication or vaccine for COVID-19</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> </span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><strong><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">How do I know if I have COVID-19? </span></span></strong></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Self Assessment - </span></span><span class="s9"><span class="bumpedFont15">If you think you have 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19) symptoms or have been in close contact with someone who has it, use this self-assessment to help determine if you need to seek further care:</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"></span></span><a href="https://www.ontario.ca/page/2019-novel-coronavirus-covid-19-self-assessment"><span class="s10"><span class="bumpedFont15">https://www.ontario.ca/page/2019-novel-coronavirus-covid-19-self-assessment</span></span></a></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s11"><span class="bumpedFont15">If you are having difficulty breathing or experiencing other severe symptoms, call 911 immediately. Advise them of your symptoms and travel history.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> </span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><strong><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Where can I get tested for COVID-19?</span></span></strong></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      COVID-19 Test sites are open around the GTA. If you think you need testing and need help locating the closest testing center to you call your local public health department or The Toronto Clinic and we will help to </span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">direct</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> you.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15"> </span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><strong><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">What is the treatment for COVID-19?</span></span></strong></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      With COVID-19 most people will only need supportive care as with the regular flu (</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">ie</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">. </span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">tylenol</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">, drink fluids, rest, stay at home) and to quarantine for 14 days.  </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Advil is not recommended.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      People who are more at risk for severe consequences of COVID-19 are those &gt;age 65, and those with pre-existing medical conditions.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> </span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><strong><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">How can I prevent getting or transmitting COVID-19?</span></span></strong></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Wash your hands</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">: Continue diligent hand washing for 30 seconds regularly while out in public, before eating and when returning home. <a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/collections/best-sellers/products/2-pack-liquid-sanitizer-500ml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em><strong>Sanitizing your hands</strong></em></a> also helps.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Stay Hydrated:</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> Sip on water every 15 minutes or so. If you have congestive heart failure or other conditions your doctor has told you to limit water intake, simply space the recommended amount throughout the day.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Social distancing</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">: The virus is spread from person to person. Most cases are spread by people with mild or even no symptoms. We should all act responsibly and minimize spreading as much as possible by avoiding crowded or public places while you have cold or flu symptoms, this includes walk-in clinics, medical clinics, and the workplace. Telecommute where possible, avoid shaking hands and do an elbow bump or foot tap instead, and consider avoiding large gatherings.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Stay home when you are sick:</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> If you are sick or feel you may be getting sick - stay home. Contact your occupational health department if available.  Encourage family members, employees, and colleagues to do the same.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s5"><span class="bumpedFont15">•</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">      </span></span><span class="s3"><span class="bumpedFont15">Minimize visiting vulnerable populations:</span></span><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15"> For example, many nursing homes have implemented restrictions on visitors to prevent spread to their residents. Be mindful not to visit those who are at risk if you are feeling ill.</span></span></p>
<p class="s8"><span class="s6"><span class="bumpedFont15">Have any questions? Feel free to contact us and our <span style="color: #e42424;"><em><strong><a href="https://medicsupplies.ca/" target="_blank" style="color: #e42424;" rel="noopener noreferrer">Medic Supplies Canada</a></strong></em></span> team will do the best to help you forward! </span></span></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
